<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ietester | Stonefishy Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://stonefishy.github.io/blog/categories/ietester/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stonefishy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2023-08-25T10:13:27+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://stonefishy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Shi]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andrewsy@163.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Run Multiple IE Version on Same Computer]]></title>
    <link href="http://stonefishy.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/how-to-run-multiple-ie-version-on-same-cotim/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T16:31:17+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://stonefishy.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/how-to-run-multiple-ie-version-on-same-cotim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As web developer, we usually need to face the challenge of making cross-browser compatible. Especially IE browser&rsquo;s multiple version. Because its quirks of rendering websites differently across its versions of <code>IE6</code>, <code>IE7</code>, <code>IE8</code> and possibly <code>IE9</code> and <code>IE10</code>.</p>

<p>Most of us have only one version of IE browser on our computer, and the compatible mode of IE is not really specific version which you want to simulate.</p>

<!-- more-->


<p>So how to run multiple version of IE on same time. Many developers install virtual machine to use the different versions. But this is not the best way.</p>

<p>In there, I will tell you there has a free tool called <code>IETester</code> can solve your problem. Use this tool can quick and easy way to run IE6, IE7, IE8 and IE9 on the same computer at the same time. And this tool just only support windows operation system. It also supports develope tool which can help developer to check web application on different version of IE.</p>

<p>This is a screen shot of <code>IETester</code>:  <br/>
<img src="/assets/images/ie-tester.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>You can download it from this address <a href="http://www.my-debugbar.com/ietester/install-ietester-v0.5.4.exe">IETester</a></p>

<p>There has another online tools called <code>Browser Sandbox</code> can solve this problem, but it is not free, if you have money, this tool will be better for you. It support any versions of <code>Firefox</code>, <code>Opera</code>, <code>Safari</code>, <code>Chrome</code> and also <code>IE</code>. You can go to this <a href="http://spoon.net/browsers/">website</a> to visit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
