<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Devops | Stonefishy Blog]]></title>
  <link href="https://stonefishy.github.io/blog/categories/devops/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://stonefishy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2023-09-02T17:26:49+08:00</updated>
  <id>https://stonefishy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Shi]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andrewsy@163.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Nginx in Mac OS X]]></title>
    <link href="https://stonefishy.github.io/blog/2015/12/05/using-nginx-in-mac-os-x/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-05T11:51:04+08:00</updated>
    <id>https://stonefishy.github.io/blog/2015/12/05/using-nginx-in-mac-os-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Introduction</h4>

<p><strong>Nginx</strong> is a open source quite lightweight HTTP server which is written by Russian <em>Igor Sysoev</em>, the pronunciation is &ldquo;engine X&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s a high performance HTTP and reverse proxy server, and also it is a IMAP/POP3/SMTP proxy server。</p>

<p>There are lots of website using Nginx in China, like Sina, Tencent, 163, Discuz and so on. The Nginx has a very high performance due to event driven way, and also it is a high performance reverse proxy, load balancing.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The features of Nginx Http server are below:</p>

<p>1.dealing with static file, indexing file and also automatically indexing.</p>

<p>2.accelerating reverse proxy server,load balancing</p>

<p>3.FastCGI, Caching, Security</p>

<p>4.Support SSL and TLS</p>

<p>From investigation, the Nginx can support about 50,000 concurrence request connection, and also support hot deploy, even running 7*24 hours uninterrupted.</p>

<h4>Installing</h4>

<p>So, how to install it on Mac OS X. Let&rsquo;s assume you have installed the <em>Home brew</em>, using brew to install the nginx with command:</p>

<pre><code>brew install nginx
</code></pre>

<h4>Starting And Runing</h4>

<p>After install, we can use below command to run it:</p>

<pre><code>sudo nginx
</code></pre>

<p>If you get the failed message which is &ldquo;[emerg] bind() to 0.0.0.0:8080 failed (48: Address already in use)&rdquo;. You have to kill the progress which is running with that address, it usually is Apache. And also there is another way, changing the port number, we will introduce later.</p>

<p>The nginx running success, you will get the below page when you access the <a href="http://localhost:8080">http://localhost:8080</a></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/nginx-welcome.png" alt="nginx, devops" /></p>

<p>There are several commands to start, stop nginx and reload configuration.</p>

<pre><code>nginx -s stop           #=&gt; fast shutdown

nginx -s quit               #=&gt; graceful shutdown

nginx -s reload         #=&gt; reloading the configuration file

nginx -s reopen         #=&gt; reopening the log files
</code></pre>

<h4>Simple Configuration</h4>

<p>The default place of nginx.conf on Mac after installing with brew is:</p>

<pre><code>/usr/local/etc/nginx/nginx.conf
</code></pre>

<p>Let&rsquo;s change the port number in this file. First, we need to stop the nginx.</p>

<pre><code>sudo nginx -s stop
</code></pre>

<p>And then open that file, you will see the below server configuration section. It includes the listen, server_name, location/root, location/index. location/root is your website root folder, and index is your website first page file.</p>

<pre><code>server {
listen       8080;          
server_name  localhost;

#access_log  logs/host.access.log  main;

location / {
    root   html;
    index  index.html index.htm;
}
</code></pre>

<p>okay, let&rsquo;s change the port number from 8080 to 80, and then run it again</p>

<pre><code>sudo nginx
</code></pre>

<p>Access it with <a href="http://localhost">http://localhost</a>, the 80 port number is http default port number, so we don&rsquo;t need to append it into url.</p>

<p>Now, let&rsquo;s put our blog website in the nginx, to do so, we need to reference the location/root to our blog website folder.</p>

<pre><code>server {
listen       80;            
server_name  localhost;

#access_log  logs/host.access.log  main;

location / {
    root   /Users/yushi/Codes/Blog/stonefishy.github.io/public;;
    index  index.html index.htm;
}
</code></pre>

<p>let&rsquo;s running it again with clicking <a href="http://localhost">http://localhost</a>. Woow, cool, very nice, we can access our blog with nignx.</p>

<p>This is a just simple usage of nginx, we will talk about more later.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
